The toughest picture ever made in Britain!
The Criminal is a crime film directed by Joseph Losey.
When a robbery at a racetrack goes wrong ex-con Johnny
Bannion is caught and sent back to prison.
He won't tell the rest of the gang where he has stashed
the loot leading to violent consequences.
Johnny Bannion, played by Stanley Baker.
Mike Carter, played by Sam Wanamaker.
Frank Saffron, played by Grégoire Aslan.
Suzanne, played by Margit Saad.
Maggie, played by Jill Bennett.
Edwards, played by Rupert Davies.
The Criminal (released in the United States as The Concrete Jungle) is a 1960 British neo-noir crime film directed by
Joseph Losey and starring Stanley Baker, Sam Wanamaker, Grégoire Aslan, Jill Bennett, and Margit Saad.
Baker plays Johnny Bannion, a recently paroled gangster (patterned after Albert Dimes) who is sent back to prison
after robbing a racetrack, with both the authorities and the criminal underworld looking for the money.
Alun Owen wrote the screenplay, from a story by an uncredited Jimmy Sangster.
John Dankworth composed the musical score, with a title song sung by Cleo Laine.
The ensemble supporting cast features Jill Bennett, Rupert Davies, Laurence
Naismith, Patrick Magee and Murray Melvin in his film debut.
The film, a  “B” melodrama  is noted for its harsh and violent portrayal of prison life
which led it to be banned in several countries, including Finland and Ireland.
The film explores themes of robbery, b movie, racetrack, british noir.
The tone is dark.